<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ArchitecTI, IT Architecure blog on IT Architecture</title>
    <link>https://architecti.blog/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ArchitecTI, IT Architecure blog on IT Architecture</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 21:07:39 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://architecti.blog/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Application Architecture – Context</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/002-architecture-applicative---mise-en-contexte/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 21:07:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/002-architecture-applicative---mise-en-contexte/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-you-concerned-with-application-architecture&#34;&gt;Are You Concerned with Application Architecture?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re a developer, you want to understand how application components interact; how a particular application workflow should run and what results to expect; and how an end user should engage with an input or display screen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re an infrastructure specialist, you need to know the type and volume of data stored and transferred; the frequency and load each application process demands; and how different application solutions fit together within the information system (IS).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to IT Architecture</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/001-presentation-architecture-informatique/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 21:07:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/001-presentation-architecture-informatique/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In today’s digital landscape, IT architecture is to a software ecosystem what foundations are to a skyscraper. It defines how systems are designed, organized, and interconnected to meet specific business objectives. A solid architecture helps reduce costs, boost resilience, and ensure agility in an ever-changing environment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post explores the main types of IT architecture: &lt;strong&gt;enterprise architecture, solution architecture, application architecture, technology architecture&lt;/strong&gt;, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-enterprise-architecture-the-strategic-framework&#34;&gt;1. Enterprise Architecture: The Strategic Framework&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enterprise architecture offers a holistic vision that aligns IT systems with business goals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 21:07:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am an IT Engineer who has held roles in technical expertise, consulting, project management, and integration and application solution architecture. Happy reading.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key Steps in Digital Transformation</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2021/002-les-%C3%A9tapes-cl%C3%A9s-de-la-transformation-num%C3%A9rique/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 21:07:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2021/002-les-%C3%A9tapes-cl%C3%A9s-de-la-transformation-num%C3%A9rique/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;Many organizations embark on digital transformation. Some succeed on their journey toward digital adoption, but few achieve the full metamorphosis promised by the new digital world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is no one-size-fits-all playbook or universal target for leaders. Every company has its own industry, operations, history, vision, workforce and financial resources.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, experience reveals key high-level prerequisites for any successful digital transformation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;observe-your-environment&#34;&gt;Observe Your Environment&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first step is to learn from peers within your industry—and beyond—to broaden your perspective. This was the theme of a November seminar organized by the World Economic Forum, attended by over twenty top executives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS vs Azure</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2021/006-aws-vs-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 21:07:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2021/006-aws-vs-azure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;opinion--comparing-the-cloud-computing-giants&#34;&gt;Opinion – Comparing the Cloud Computing Giants&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;KINSTA is an American WordPress hosting provider that publishes in-depth blog articles on various themes. While reading “AWS vs Azure in 2021 (Comparing the Cloud Computing Giants),” I discovered several interesting insights to share.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cloud-computing-players&#34;&gt;Cloud Computing Players&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The rapid growth in cloud demand has spawned an exponential increase in services and options. The broader your target, the more use cases you must support and the more products you need to offer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Myths About Digital Transformation</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2021/005-4-mythes-sur-la-transformation-num%C3%A9rique/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 21:17:30 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2021/005-4-mythes-sur-la-transformation-num%C3%A9rique/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Digital transformation is far from a new concept. In recent years, companies have rapidly adopted technologies—from the Internet of Things (IoT) and blockchain to chatbots, machine learning, and virtual reality. Almost every organization engages in some form of digital transformation, yet few truly reap its benefits.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Bain &amp;amp; Company analysis found that fewer than 10 percent of global enterprises actually achieve their forecasted results from digital investments. In other words, over 90 percent still struggle to fulfill the promise of a technology-driven business model.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Innovate in IT Architecture</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2021/004-comment-innover-en-architecture-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 21:18:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2021/004-comment-innover-en-architecture-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have just reviewed the Boston Consulting Group report, “Most Innovative Companies 2021 – Overcoming the Innovation Readiness Gap – April 2021.” Let’s explore how to innovate in IT architecture.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This report summarizes interviews with 1,500 innovation leaders worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The key takeaway is that innovation has become one of the top three priorities for their organizations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before examining how innovation applies to IT architecture, let’s walk through this report.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One striking aspect of the top 50 most innovative companies list is the dominance of technology firms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Differences Between TOGAF and ArchiMate</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2021/003-diff%C3%A9rences-entre-togaf-et-archimate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 21:07:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2021/003-diff%C3%A9rences-entre-togaf-et-archimate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Answering the question of the differences between TOGAF and ArchiMate is not straightforward, but here’s what you need to know.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most organizations today are embarking on or renewing their enterprise architecture practices. Is yours part of that trend?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If so, you’re not alone—many enterprise architects are confused by the distinctions between TOGAF and ArchiMate. While there are overlaps, each standard serves a distinct purpose. Which one should you learn first?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which Application Architecture to Choose</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2021/001-quelle-architecture-applicative-choisir/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 21:07:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2021/001-quelle-architecture-applicative-choisir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Choosing an Application Architecture is a pivotal decision impacting team structure, workflows, technology choices, skill requirements, and interactions with internal users, clients, and partners. So, which application architecture in 2021?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;preface&#34;&gt;Preface&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article focuses not on technology vendors or platforms but on architectural choices. Given the multitude of technical solutions across diverse scenarios, covering them all in one piece is impossible. Future posts will address specific technologies, which are equally important.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solution Architecture – Designing Around a Specific Problem</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2020/004-architecture-de-solution--conception-autour-dune-probl%C3%A9matique-pr%C3%A9cise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 21:07:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2020/004-architecture-de-solution--conception-autour-dune-probl%C3%A9matique-pr%C3%A9cise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Solution Architecture is the least well-defined component of Enterprise Architecture. In other words, the same term can encompass activities with differing scopes. Yet demand for Solution Architects continues to grow, highlighting the role’s rising importance. Let’s clarify its contours.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-solution-architecture&#34;&gt;What Is Solution Architecture?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to Gartner, Solution Architecture is the architectural description of a specific solution—a coherent and sufficient set of features that addresses a defined set of requirements.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Scaled Agile Framework (SAFe) describes Solution Architecture as defining and communicating a shared architectural and technical vision for work in progress.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Architecture or Governance of Enterprise Information</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2020/003-architecture-de-donn%C3%A9es-ou-la-gouvernance-de-linformation-d-entreprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 21:07:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2020/003-architecture-de-donn%C3%A9es-ou-la-gouvernance-de-linformation-d-entreprise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data Architecture is one of the components of Enterprise Architecture. It focuses on the rules for managing and organizing data.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Be careful not to confuse defining data practices with their implementation, which is handled by more technical roles; nor with the Chief Data Officer, a leadership role responsible for all data-related matters across the organization.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The importance of a comprehensive, up-to-date Data Architecture is growing. Data is collected, transformed, stored, and exchanged at an ever-increasing pace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technology Architecture or Technical Architecture vs Technical Expertise</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2020/002-architecture-technologique-ou-architecture-technique-vs-expertise-technique/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 21:07:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2020/002-architecture-technologique-ou-architecture-technique-vs-expertise-technique/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Beyond the terms that may vary from one organization or methodology to another, it’s essential to understand what defines Technology Architecture (or Technical Architecture) and what distinguishes it from Technical Expertise.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s therefore necessary to separate governance roles from implementation roles. Both are crucial, and individuals can navigate between them over the course of a career.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Within Enterprise Architecture, Technology Architecture focuses on functionality—data persistence, executing workloads tied to a business process, and so on. Its goal is to organize, standardize, and govern the use of technologies in implementing the Application Architecture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enterprise Architecture or Governance of IS Design</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2020/001-architecture-d-entreprise-ou-la-gouvernance-de-la-conception-du-si/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 21:07:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2020/001-architecture-d-entreprise-ou-la-gouvernance-de-la-conception-du-si/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Enterprise Architecture establishes, enforces and evolves the guiding design principles of the Information System (IS). It is, in essence, the governance of IS design—from urbanizing the IS, through data governance, to application design.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To avoid reinventing the wheel and to speak a common language across and within organizations, reference frameworks provide standard terminologies and methodologies. These frameworks may focus on process or on graphical representation. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://architecti.blog/posts/diff%C3%A9rences-entre-togaf-et-archimate/&#34;&gt;Differences between TOGAF and ArchiMate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Find</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/tagslist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/tagslist/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
