<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloud on IT Architecture</title>
    <link>https://architecti.blog/en/tags/cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloud on IT Architecture</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 07:30:39 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://architecti.blog/en/tags/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Monolithic Architecture: Foundations, Strengths, and Limitations of a Classic Style</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/011-architecture-monolithique---fondations-forces-et-limites/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 07:30:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/011-architecture-monolithique---fondations-forces-et-limites/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Monolithic architecture is one of the oldest and most widespread styles in software development. It is often seen as the natural starting point for many applications, especially in contexts where simplicity, rapid implementation, and consistency are key priorities. Although modern architectures such as microservices or serverless have gained popularity, the monolith remains highly relevant in many use cases. This article offers an in-depth exploration of this architectural style, highlighting its characteristics, advantages, limitations, and how it compares to other approaches.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Serverless Architecture: Revolutionizing Web Development Without Servers</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/010-architecture-serverless---r%C3%A9volutionner-le-d%C3%A9veloppement-web-sans-serveur/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:30:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/010-architecture-serverless---r%C3%A9volutionner-le-d%C3%A9veloppement-web-sans-serveur/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;serverless architecture&amp;rdquo; may raise a few questions—let’s demystify it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Serverless architecture is revolutionizing how modern applications are designed and deployed by offloading infrastructure management to cloud providers. Instead of provisioning, configuring, and maintaining dedicated servers or virtual machine clusters, development teams can focus on writing business logic. This paradigm directly addresses the agility and responsiveness demanded by today’s businesses, which aim to reduce time-to-market while optimizing operational costs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microservices Architecture: Principles, Benefits, Challenges, and Use Cases</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/009-l-architecture-microservices--une-r%C3%A9volution-dans-la-conception-applicative/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 16:45:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/009-l-architecture-microservices--une-r%C3%A9volution-dans-la-conception-applicative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In recent years, software development has undergone a profound transformation in how applications are designed, deployed, and maintained. This shift is largely driven by the rise of microservices architecture, which stands in contrast to traditional monolithic systems. In a world where businesses must innovate quickly, adapt to changing user needs, and ensure high availability, microservices offer a flexible and scalable solution to modern challenges. Yet behind this promise lies a set of technical, organizational, and cultural decisions that deserve careful exploration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS vs Azure</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2021/006-aws-vs-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 21:07:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2021/006-aws-vs-azure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;opinion--comparing-the-cloud-computing-giants&#34;&gt;Opinion – Comparing the Cloud Computing Giants&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;KINSTA is an American WordPress hosting provider that publishes in-depth blog articles on various themes. While reading “AWS vs Azure in 2021 (Comparing the Cloud Computing Giants),” I discovered several interesting insights to share.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cloud-computing-players&#34;&gt;Cloud Computing Players&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The rapid growth in cloud demand has spawned an exponential increase in services and options. The broader your target, the more use cases you must support and the more products you need to offer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
