<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>All Articles in 2025 on IT Architecture</title>
    <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/</link>
    <description>Recent content in All Articles in 2025 on IT Architecture</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 16:45:39 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Microservices Architecture: Principles, Benefits, Challenges, and Use Cases</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/009-l-architecture-microservices--une-r%C3%A9volution-dans-la-conception-applicative/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 16:45:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/009-l-architecture-microservices--une-r%C3%A9volution-dans-la-conception-applicative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In recent years, software development has undergone a profound transformation in how applications are designed, deployed, and maintained. This shift is largely driven by the rise of microservices architecture, which stands in contrast to traditional monolithic systems. In a world where businesses must innovate quickly, adapt to changing user needs, and ensure high availability, microservices offer a flexible and scalable solution to modern challenges. Yet behind this promise lies a set of technical, organizational, and cultural decisions that deserve careful exploration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Fundamental Principles of Domain-Driven Design (DDD)</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/008-les-principes-fondamentaux-du-domain-driven-design-ddd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 21:07:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/008-les-principes-fondamentaux-du-domain-driven-design-ddd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As software systems grow increasingly complex, it becomes essential to design architectures that accurately reflect business needs. That’s the core goal of &lt;strong&gt;Domain-Driven Design (DDD)&lt;/strong&gt;, an approach introduced by &lt;strong&gt;Eric Evans&lt;/strong&gt; in 2003 that places the &lt;strong&gt;business domain&lt;/strong&gt; at the heart of software design.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DDD is more than a modeling method—it’s a &lt;strong&gt;design philosophy&lt;/strong&gt; that deeply influences application architecture by guiding component structure, responsibility definition, and system communication.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article explores the &lt;strong&gt;10 fundamental principles of DDD&lt;/strong&gt;, with concrete examples and architectural impacts, especially in &lt;strong&gt;microservices&lt;/strong&gt; contexts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Agile Methodology Is Hard to Apply in IT Projects (And How to Do It Better)</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/007-la-difficult%C3%A9-dappliquer-la-m%C3%A9thodologie-agile-dans-les-projets-informatiques/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 21:17:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/007-la-difficult%C3%A9-dappliquer-la-m%C3%A9thodologie-agile-dans-les-projets-informatiques/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;work-methodologies-in-it--from-waterfall-to-agile&#34;&gt;Work Methodologies in IT – From Waterfall to Agile&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For decades, IT project management relied on structured, sequential methodologies, with the waterfall model being the most iconic. This model follows a linear progression of project phases: starting with a detailed requirements analysis, followed by design, development, testing, and finally deployment and maintenance. Each phase must be completed before moving to the next, offering a certain level of rigor and visibility over timelines and costs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neuromorphic Architecture: How Brain-Inspired Computing Is Shaping the Future of AI</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/006-l-architecture-neuromorphique/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 21:07:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/006-l-architecture-neuromorphique/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;neuromorphic-architecture-how-brain-inspired-computing-is-shaping-the-future-of-ai&#34;&gt;Neuromorphic Architecture: How Brain-Inspired Computing Is Shaping the Future of AI&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-when-computing-imitates-the-brain&#34;&gt;Introduction: When Computing Imitates the Brain&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the early days of computing, engineers have dreamed of replicating human cognition through machines. While traditional computers have revolutionized logic, communication, and data processing, they remain fundamentally different from the human brain in structure and behavior.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enter &lt;strong&gt;neuromorphic architecture&lt;/strong&gt; — a cutting-edge approach that designs computing systems inspired by the biological mechanisms of the brain. Unlike conventional AI, which simulates neural networks in software, neuromorphic systems aim to &lt;strong&gt;physically replicate neurons, synapses, and sensory pathways&lt;/strong&gt; in electronic circuits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern Application Architecture: How Microservices, APIs, and Cloud Drive Digital Transformation</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/005-l-architecture-applicative-moderne---moteur-de-la-transformation-num%C3%A9rique/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 21:07:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/005-l-architecture-applicative-moderne---moteur-de-la-transformation-num%C3%A9rique/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;modern-application-architecture-how-microservices-apis-and-cloud-drive-digital-transformation&#34;&gt;Modern Application Architecture: How Microservices, APIs, and Cloud Drive Digital Transformation&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-application-architecture-matters-in-the-digital-age&#34;&gt;Why Application Architecture Matters in the Digital Age&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In today’s fast-paced digital landscape, businesses must evolve rapidly to stay competitive. Behind every seamless user experience and innovative product lies a robust &lt;strong&gt;application architecture&lt;/strong&gt; — the backbone of scalable, secure, and agile systems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modern architecture isn’t just a technical upgrade. It’s a strategic enabler of &lt;strong&gt;digital transformation&lt;/strong&gt;, allowing organizations to innovate faster, reduce costs, and deliver better customer experiences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Bounded Context in Microservices Architecture: A Key to Scalable Software Design</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/004-comprendre-le-bounded-context-en-architecture-microservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 21:07:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/004-comprendre-le-bounded-context-en-architecture-microservices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microservices architecture is a modern software design approach that has transformed how scalable and maintainable systems are built. It’s based on the principle of decomposing a monolithic application into a series of independent services, each responsible for a well-defined business domain. But this decomposition raises a crucial question: &lt;strong&gt;how do we define the boundaries of each microservice?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is where the concept of &lt;strong&gt;bounded context&lt;/strong&gt;, introduced by &lt;strong&gt;Domain-Driven Design (DDD)&lt;/strong&gt;, becomes essential. It helps structure microservices around coherent business models, avoiding ambiguity and unnecessary dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application Architecture: Designing Robust and Adaptable Systems</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/003-architecture-applicative---concevoir-des-syst%C3%A8mes-robustes-et-adaptables/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 21:07:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/003-architecture-applicative---concevoir-des-syst%C3%A8mes-robustes-et-adaptables/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a constantly evolving digital landscape, user requirements and technological constraints proliferate. A thoughtful application architecture does more than organize code: it defines a holistic strategy to decouple responsibilities and optimize performance, scalability, and resilience. This engineering discipline is essential for organizations aiming to stay competitive and agile.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;foundations-and-definitions&#34;&gt;Foundations and Definitions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Application architecture encompasses the rules, components, and interfaces that structure an application. It includes:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Separation of Concerns&lt;/strong&gt;: Breaking the application into modules or layers with clear responsibilities to simplify understanding, testing, and maintenance.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modularity&lt;/strong&gt;: Designing independent, reusable components that can be deployed and updated in isolation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design Patterns&lt;/strong&gt;: Applying proven models—such as Model-View-Controller, layered architectures, or microservices—to standardize and streamline software structure.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Together, these principles enable flexible environments where technical evolution and functional changes integrate smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application Architecture – Context</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/002-architecture-applicative---mise-en-contexte/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 21:07:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/002-architecture-applicative---mise-en-contexte/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-you-concerned-with-application-architecture&#34;&gt;Are You Concerned with Application Architecture?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re a developer, you want to understand how application components interact; how a particular application workflow should run and what results to expect; and how an end user should engage with an input or display screen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re an infrastructure specialist, you need to know the type and volume of data stored and transferred; the frequency and load each application process demands; and how different application solutions fit together within the information system (IS).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to IT Architecture</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/001-presentation-architecture-informatique/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 21:07:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/001-presentation-architecture-informatique/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In today’s digital landscape, IT architecture is to a software ecosystem what foundations are to a skyscraper. It defines how systems are designed, organized, and interconnected to meet specific business objectives. A solid architecture helps reduce costs, boost resilience, and ensure agility in an ever-changing environment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post explores the main types of IT architecture: &lt;strong&gt;enterprise architecture, solution architecture, application architecture, technology architecture&lt;/strong&gt;, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-enterprise-architecture-the-strategic-framework&#34;&gt;1. Enterprise Architecture: The Strategic Framework&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enterprise architecture offers a holistic vision that aligns IT systems with business goals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
