<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Transformation on IT Architecture</title>
    <link>https://architecti.blog/en/tags/digital-transformation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Digital Transformation on IT Architecture</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 21:07:39 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://architecti.blog/en/tags/digital-transformation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Key Steps in Digital Transformation</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2021/002-les-%C3%A9tapes-cl%C3%A9s-de-la-transformation-num%C3%A9rique/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 21:07:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2021/002-les-%C3%A9tapes-cl%C3%A9s-de-la-transformation-num%C3%A9rique/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;Many organizations embark on digital transformation. Some succeed on their journey toward digital adoption, but few achieve the full metamorphosis promised by the new digital world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is no one-size-fits-all playbook or universal target for leaders. Every company has its own industry, operations, history, vision, workforce and financial resources.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, experience reveals key high-level prerequisites for any successful digital transformation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;observe-your-environment&#34;&gt;Observe Your Environment&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first step is to learn from peers within your industry—and beyond—to broaden your perspective. This was the theme of a November seminar organized by the World Economic Forum, attended by over twenty top executives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Myths About Digital Transformation</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2021/005-4-mythes-sur-la-transformation-num%C3%A9rique/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 21:17:30 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2021/005-4-mythes-sur-la-transformation-num%C3%A9rique/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Digital transformation is far from a new concept. In recent years, companies have rapidly adopted technologies—from the Internet of Things (IoT) and blockchain to chatbots, machine learning, and virtual reality. Almost every organization engages in some form of digital transformation, yet few truly reap its benefits.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Bain &amp;amp; Company analysis found that fewer than 10 percent of global enterprises actually achieve their forecasted results from digital investments. In other words, over 90 percent still struggle to fulfill the promise of a technology-driven business model.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
