<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microservices on IT Architecture</title>
    <link>https://architecti.blog/en/tags/microservices/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Microservices on IT Architecture</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 16:45:39 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://architecti.blog/en/tags/microservices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Microservices Architecture: Principles, Benefits, Challenges, and Use Cases</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/009-l-architecture-microservices--une-r%C3%A9volution-dans-la-conception-applicative/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 16:45:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/009-l-architecture-microservices--une-r%C3%A9volution-dans-la-conception-applicative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In recent years, software development has undergone a profound transformation in how applications are designed, deployed, and maintained. This shift is largely driven by the rise of microservices architecture, which stands in contrast to traditional monolithic systems. In a world where businesses must innovate quickly, adapt to changing user needs, and ensure high availability, microservices offer a flexible and scalable solution to modern challenges. Yet behind this promise lies a set of technical, organizational, and cultural decisions that deserve careful exploration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Fundamental Principles of Domain-Driven Design (DDD)</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/008-les-principes-fondamentaux-du-domain-driven-design-ddd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 21:07:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/008-les-principes-fondamentaux-du-domain-driven-design-ddd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As software systems grow increasingly complex, it becomes essential to design architectures that accurately reflect business needs. That’s the core goal of &lt;strong&gt;Domain-Driven Design (DDD)&lt;/strong&gt;, an approach introduced by &lt;strong&gt;Eric Evans&lt;/strong&gt; in 2003 that places the &lt;strong&gt;business domain&lt;/strong&gt; at the heart of software design.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DDD is more than a modeling method—it’s a &lt;strong&gt;design philosophy&lt;/strong&gt; that deeply influences application architecture by guiding component structure, responsibility definition, and system communication.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article explores the &lt;strong&gt;10 fundamental principles of DDD&lt;/strong&gt;, with concrete examples and architectural impacts, especially in &lt;strong&gt;microservices&lt;/strong&gt; contexts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern Application Architecture: How Microservices, APIs, and Cloud Drive Digital Transformation</title>
      <link>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/005-l-architecture-applicative-moderne---moteur-de-la-transformation-num%C3%A9rique/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 21:07:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://architecti.blog/en/articles/2025/005-l-architecture-applicative-moderne---moteur-de-la-transformation-num%C3%A9rique/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;modern-application-architecture-how-microservices-apis-and-cloud-drive-digital-transformation&#34;&gt;Modern Application Architecture: How Microservices, APIs, and Cloud Drive Digital Transformation&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-application-architecture-matters-in-the-digital-age&#34;&gt;Why Application Architecture Matters in the Digital Age&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In today’s fast-paced digital landscape, businesses must evolve rapidly to stay competitive. Behind every seamless user experience and innovative product lies a robust &lt;strong&gt;application architecture&lt;/strong&gt; — the backbone of scalable, secure, and agile systems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modern architecture isn’t just a technical upgrade. It’s a strategic enabler of &lt;strong&gt;digital transformation&lt;/strong&gt;, allowing organizations to innovate faster, reduce costs, and deliver better customer experiences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
